My name is Candace. I build software.

I'm ready to begin a new chapter. I long for meaningful work that connects my heart to the world. I want to help people. I've been around the block, and I think it is time to put all these skills, this experience, and this potential to the right use.

My priorities are to grow personally, technically, and as a leader.



This is me, directing plants.

Skills

Architecture Engineering Design & UX Ops Leadership

Technologies

Languages

Python, PHP, Javascript, regex, CSS, HTML, SASS, Coffeescript

Libraries

Django, Laravel, Lumen, Vue, Ember, Backbone, Node, CakePHP, Yii, Zend, Craft, Wordpress, Symfony, D3

Data

MySQL, Redis, Postgres, Neo4j

Education

The Art Institute of Portland

BS, Multimedia & Web Design - 2002 - 2006 Graduated with Honors and Class Speaker

University of Oregon School of Music

Violin Performance Program - 1998 - 2001

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Vacasa | April 2015 - present

Lead the architecture and engineering of services central to the company's ability to scale. I've generally focused on building smaller modern REST services to replace legacy monolithic business logic. I designed a long-term business logic migration plan, involving creation of an ORM "shim" between legacy business logic and long term technology objectives.

Senior Developer

Owen Jones & Partners | November 2013 - March 2015 Technical lead and developer on a variety of interactive projects, including web applications, mobile-friendly websites, and CMS integrations.

Senior Software Developer, Interactive Developer

CMD Agency | November 2011 - November 2013 Lead and team engineer for full-stack web applications, mobile applications, microsites, and email campaigns. Working with front-end and back-end technologies such as Zend, Bootstrap, and MySQL.

Designer, Developer, Owner

Candace Lapp Design, LLC | June 2006 - November 2011 Working directly with clients, I designed and developed projects ranging from business cards to full-stack web applications, motion graphics, and Flash applications.

Interactive Media Designer / Developer

Chamber Music Northwest | April 2005 - July 2006
Designed, engineered, and maintained this non-profit music organization's data-driven website. Worked with multiple stakeholders to produce a LAMP-stack application that managed artist profiles, concert schedules, music clips, a blog, and venue information.

Webmaster / User Support Assistant

University of Oregon Department of Public Safety
October 1999 - December 2001
Designed, developed, and maintained this campus security
department's website using front-end technologies.
Provided IT assistance and user support.